#### Mohammed Mazoir

French / Moroccan

*Age:* 35 (Date of birth: July 11<sup>th</sup>, 1975)

Married (2 children)

<u>Telephone</u> - Cellular: +33 (0)6.17.01.36.19 - Home: +33(0)4.42.63.28.36

Email: mohammed.mazoir@gmail.com

Address: Résidence Tivoli, Bâtiment 31, 6 allée des Peupliers, 13090 Aix en Provence, France

#### OBJECTIVE:

Senior Electronics Engineer certified Lean Six Sigma Black Belt with 14+ years of experience (France and Morocco). I am specialized in transverse continuous improvement, industrial performance optimization, cost reduction and change management. Objective: to obtain a challenging position in charge of continuous improvement, process excellence and/or Lean Six Sigma.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

- 01/2010 – Present: Executive Member, Coleman Research Group, United States of America: Advice about the semiconductor industry trends.

# - 02/2005 - Present: Lean Six Sigma Black Belt in charge of continuous improvement, Senior Test Methods Engineer, ATMEL, Rousset, France:

As a Lean Six Sigma Black Belt, I am the first in charge of the deployment of continuous improvement and Process Excellence overall the company in France (two sites: Rousset and Nantes). As an internal consultant, I provide active leadership and support to all departments of the company such as: design, human resources, purchasing, customer service, marketing and manufacturing to identify, select and lead transverse continuous improvement projects in order to reduce cost, improve quality and customer satisfaction, optimize industrial performance and reduce time to market for new advanced products and technologies.

I am an adviser to the top management to identify and select projects with high added value for the company and justified return on investment. Now, I report to the business management director and I work closely with all managers to promote the process excellence and Lean Six Sigma and develop a global approach to improve the business through transverse and cross-functional continuous improvement.

I am responsible of establishment of yearly roadmap and deployment policy. I organize regular project review with the steering committee. I give regular training and mentoring of employees at all levels (1500 people) following the cascade training model, coaching of Green Belt and Black Belt (2 Black Belt certification in progress).

I promote the continuous improvement approach and exchange of best practices on a group level where I am recognized as the first specialist. I also give training to employees from other sites (USA, Norway, China, and Germany).

My main skills are:

- Change management.
- Ability to deal with Blue collar and White Collar workers as well as communicate with the CEO and all top management persons.
- Lean and Six Sigma: DMAIC, Kaizen, 5S, VSM, SIPOC, SMED, TPM, 5Why, Design of experiment and advanced statistical analysis.
- Strong experience in equipment maintenance: Cost reduction, downtime reduction.
- Ability to negotiate the objectives and the means to achieve them.

My main achievements are:

- Reduce wafer manufacturing cost from \$1100 to 800\$ (all the site of Rousset was involved).
- Reduce the absenteeism rate from 7% to 2.5% (Human Resources project).
- Reduce Engineering time on equipment: cost reduction 150K\$ during one year.
- Improve customer satisfaction from 90% to 95%.

# - 02/2004 – 01/2005: Product Engineer in charge of continuous improvement, ATMEL, Rousset, France:

The purpose of this work was to establish new methodologies of data analysis for the advanced technologies in the microelectronics industry. These methodologies were developed from studies and analyses of products and current working principles followed by various stakeholders. The field of action extended from order to delivery of electronics integrated circuits (design, manufacturing, assembly, final test). The methodologies were accompanied with a proposal defining a new software tool allowing their display for the future technological generations. This study lead to significant cost saving, indeed about 400K\$ for the first year.

## - 01/2001 – 01/2004: Maintenance and Equipment Engineering, ATMEL, Rousset, France

Performing preventive and corrective maintenance operations on manufacturing equipments in the Fab. Deployment of TPM culture to improve equipment availability and reduce maintenance cost.

My main results are:

- Improve equipment availability by 35%.
- Reduce maintenance cost by 20%.

#### - 04/1997 – 12/2000: Maintenance Team Leader, STMicroelectronics, Casablanca, Morocco

Performing preventive and corrective maintenance on manufacturing equipments at the test and finish level. Looking for second sources for spare parts to reduce costs. Participating in the deployment of TQM (Total Quality Management) and responsible of deployment of TPM (Total Productive Maintenance). Management of a team of 60 people during 9 months.

My main results are:

- Improve equipment availability by 30%.
- Reduce maintenance cost by 25%.

## - 09/1996 - 03/1997: Team Leader, VEIL'24, Casablanca, Morocco

Supervising the installation of electronic security systems (access control, intrusion detection, Video surveillance and fire safety). Management of a 12 person team.

# - 04/1996 – 06/1996: Trainee at the Electro technical Research and Development Laboratory, Oujda, Morocco:

Implementing a new computer aided system to study electrical devices (electrical motors).

# **EDUCATION & TRAINING**

### **Additional training:**

- > Lean Six Sigma Green Belt and Black Belt certification including change management.
- > Human resources management.
- > Continuous improvement and cost reduction project management.
- 2002-05: Master's Degree in Electronic Engineering.

Conservatoire National des Arts et Métiers, Aix en Provence, France.

- **2002-04: Higher Level Diploma (French High Technical Studies Diploma) in Electronics.** Conservatoire National des Arts et Métiers, Aix en Provence, France.
- **2002-03:** University Higher Level Diploma (French University High Technical Studies Diploma) in Electronics. Université de Provence, Marseille, France.
- 1997-99: University Degree in Electronics, Robotics and Industrial Computer Programming. Institut supérieur du Génie Appliqué (IGA), Casablanca, Morocco.
- 1994-96: Two-year University Diploma (French University Diploma of Technology) in Electronics. Ecole Supérieure de Technologie, Université Mohammed 1<sup>er</sup>, Oujda, Morocco.
- **1991-94: High School Degree (French Baccalaureate) in Electronics.** Lycée Technique Errazi, ElJadida, Morocco.

## **ACHIEVEMENT**

**University Degree Final Year Project:** Design and manufacturing of an Integrated Circuits tester. The system was developed to test and identify a wide range of circuits.

# **LANGUAGES**

- Arabic: Mother tongue.
- French: Bilingual.
- English: Solid working knowledge (Good skills, both written and oral).
- Chinese: Basic knowledge.

## COMPUTER KNOWLEDGE

Computer skills: Windows, MS Word, MS Excel, MS PowerPoint.

Programming languages: C++, C, Python, Pascal, Basic, Assembler (CPU and MCU).

## **ACTIVITIES AND INTERESTS**

- Sports: Hiking, Football, Volleyball and table tennis.
- Traveling.

## REFERENCES

References available upon request.

LinkedIn profile available at: <a href="http://fr.linkedin.com/in/mohammedmazoir">http://fr.linkedin.com/in/mohammedmazoir</a>